<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-18T20:17:24+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Prateek Srivastava</title><subtitle>This is a WIP. First cut is just getting the bare essentials out there.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Completing the first draft</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/01/first-draft-done.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Completing the first draft" /><published>2018-03-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/03/01/first-draft-done</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/01/first-draft-done.html">&lt;p&gt;5 months of the sabbatical just flew by. There was a lot that I did during these months, but most importantly, I completed my first draft!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took some extreme hardwork, focus and determination to get the first draft done. And surprisingly, the major chunk of it was done in the last month. To say that I was relieved would be an understatement. I had bet too much on this, and at a point during the break I was worried that at the end, I would have nothing to show for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holding the complete first draft in my hands, at the end of the 5 months, made me feel ecstatic. I had crossed the first hurdle!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">5 months of the sabbatical just flew by. There was a lot that I did during these months, but most importantly, I completed my first draft!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Taking time off for writing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/01/taking-time-off.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taking time off for writing" /><published>2017-09-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-09-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/01/taking-time-off</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/01/taking-time-off.html">&lt;p&gt;The idea of Divnity was brewing in my head for a while. I had formed the characters in my head, thought of an intriguing setting, and come up with riveting scenes that appealed to me. I just had to sit down, and bring it all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally decided that I needed time off to write, and only write, if I was to complete my first draft. It was a daunting task to take a sabbatical, but I had to give myself a chance to do this. I did not want any regrets later in life, especially since I believed that Divinity as a story had great potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took 5 months off work, from October to February. This break was going to hamper my career growth in Software Development by at least a year, but I was mentally prepared for it. I knew what was at stake, and I was prepared to make the sacrifices it required. I put in the sabbatical request, and my journey started from the first day of October 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The idea of Divnity was brewing in my head for a while. I had formed the characters in my head, thought of an intriguing setting, and come up with riveting scenes that appealed to me. I just had to sit down, and bring it all together.</summary></entry></feed>